hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
microkowski and on this podcast we show
you ways to grow your coaching business
your course business to reach more
clients how to find your Niche how to
get more clients how to get more people
paying you for what you're doing so that
you can make more money and grow your
business now today I want to actually
share with you something from a live
event that we did this weekend called
funnels and offer copy live I broke down
in probably the easiest to understand
way I've ever done before what a funnel
is and a lot of people said that this
gave them so much Clarity for their
business that this one training I I had
to put it out there for the rest of you
this clip from this live event it was an
all-day event I plan on doing another
future all-day event maybe a two-day
event like this it will cost money it's
not going to be a free event about
funnels and offer copy but this training
right here as is from this event that I
just did all about funnels and how a
funnel works and what a funnel is so
that you can visualize exactly what your
funnel is I've also included a link to
another podcast episode that I did it's
in the description of the podcast it's
episode number
169. 169 of this podcast it's called
funnels that make seven figures for
coaches with Steven Robbins and we broke
down together Steven is the guy who
builds my funnels and you can actually
hire him to build your funnels as well
we broke down about funnels and for
coaches and four course creators and so
you can take this as well as the PDF
that's linked as well as this lesson and
really get a really good picture of what
a funnel is so that you can have Clarity
in your business instead of struggling
and wondering okay how does this all
work together how is this all going to
fit together that's one of the biggest
things a lot of people say is I don't
know how all the pieces are going to fit
together Jeremiah this episode is going
to answer that question for you so stay
tuned let's get that right into it
let's talk about a funnel okay
so that was an example of writing copy
you're like well this is called funnels
and offer copy yes because they go hand
in hand
so a funnel
is you figure out your words your
messaging right here that's words and
messaging that you could translate and
use those keywords in your social media
content
you would base your content off of that
you would base your offers off of that
you would base your ads off of that one
idea
as you start to run more offers around
that you're going to learn more from the
people that are actually registering
with you about the very specific
problems they have so if you're finding
that 80 percent of them have a very
specific issue you want to put that
issue at the top of your copy
because it's going to identify your
buyers faster
it's going to identify them much faster
by their specific issue because it's
going to resonate with those exact
people and your cost will go down in
your advertising and marketing and the
algorithm will actually show your
content to people with those specific
issues versus a general issue okay now a
funnel
a funnel is
is this
can you just see me on the screen guys
nope
am I up on the screen well yeah but
there's like a title of everyone like
normal like a great okay I gotcha if you
change it to speaker view you should be
able to see
do you want us to it's up to you that
way you can see the Whiteboard better
got it
um so a funnel
is
I'm more do a funnel this way but it's
really it's like this
this is your social media
and your ads
this is your offers
this is what you have for sale
and then you have
uh like
a VIP like level like higher level
coaching like a ten thousand dollar
and then this is your like ultimate like
50 to 100
um even up to like mine is now two
hundred and fifty thousand
so a value ladder and a funnel are very
similar to each other
what a funnel does though is it's it's
each level in this
helps you sort the people
through their level of commitment
and so when you run an offer out there
and you capture their email address
or they they like your your content on
social media
they're joining your funnel
and so now the goal is for those same
people
to be served
qualified
and made offers to to get them to give
you money
and so in your funnel a funnel could be
as simple as okay we have a one-day
event
for for one day we're gonna go over all
this information
and then at the end of it I'm going to
tell you Hey listen if you want to go to
the next level I have a five-day event
that I'm doing in two weeks
and you can upgrade to VIP for 47 bucks
and have me
answering your questions working with
you in your business but even if you
don't want to do that this five-day
event if you're somebody that is just
starting with your Niche we this is
after we did our our thing so we spent a
whole day together working on their
Niche we spent a whole day together
working on ways that they can improve
their skin we spent a whole day together
working with them on how to get
breakthrough in their life how to get
breakthrough with their Fitness how to
get breakthrough with their
um
the way that they communicate with
people the way that they talk the way
that they connect with people how to get
breakthrough with their mental health
and their trauma and their issue see so
so you're gonna spend a day with them
doing that and so this is what we call
top of funnel
you either spend a whole day doing that
and here's a cool thing you take the
transcript of the whole day deal and you
can then edit the transcript in Jasper
and now you have a 12-page 20-page eBook
you publish that on Amazon
you get it printed you ship it to them
for 10 like 10 shipping or something and
now you have a book funnel
off of the same information from your
webinar
now you don't have to do all of this by
the way just okay hear me out
see it because I just talked about a
whole bunch of stuff that you got to do
you only need one offer
one offer
and you just make off one offer and then
after you make that offer you make
another offer
and then you make another offer and
another offer and another offer and you
keep doing this to people and making
them offers and most people by the way
need to be made at least seven to ten
offers before they ever buy from you
and and and and that's just because that
it takes that long for them to build
trust with you
now as you hone in your Niche you can
make them one offer and get them at that
point that's where your business becomes
profitable because the ones who sign up
on one offer or two offers
will will make your business
um the initial profit margin but you're
going to have a lot of people they're
going to go through three or four of
your webinars for free
that you do or hop on a 77 event with
you or buy one class with you for 47
bucks
an intro those are all parts of your
funnel anything that's under ninety
seven dollars is top of funnel
if it's under a hundred bucks it's top
of funnel to build trust with people
and the cheaper it is the less committed
they are and the less qualified they are
overall now you'll have a lot of
qualified people that jump into your
free stuff
but you'll also have a majority that are
not qualified for instance
um 10 of everybody who came through my
five day thing joined this program
okay so I got I got 35 37 I think new
people into this program off of that
five-day building your coaching business
deal
okay that added like six six thousand a
month to our our business
and I it paid for itself on the VIP on
the five-day event
and so now I'm taking a portion of that
and I'm running a free event and so
that's top of funnel
with what your offer is and your offer
messaging is based off of what solution
that you help people with so you're
essentially inviting people here's how
you need to look at your offers really I
want to make it
probably the simplest that I've ever
shared it with people
it's high I'm Jeremiah
come to my house and I'm going to show
you how to accomplish this problem that
you have
now because that sounds really creepy
and you don't want people coming to your
house that are random strangers that's
why we meet over Zoom meetings
you know and people are willing to even
I don't want to show my face I don't
want to put my camera up we'll meet in a
Facebook group and they'll watch you
give your little Spiel and teach and
bring value
on just about anything if you offer it
for free for them to come check it out
you'll always have a group of people
that want to at least listen to you
share about some topic if they don't
okay you're either targeting the wrong
people or your offer is completely off
that's it
you're either targeting the wrong people
you're trying to sell be like Monica go
into a an all-male biker gang of bold
men and trying to get them to sign up
for her stuff like not a single she'd
probably get half of them doing it just
because they thought she was cute but
like she's not gonna get all of them to
sign up because they don't want it
they'll maybe buy it for their
girlfriend right you know but but like
she's gonna do way better to just get
those women in the room with her
to getting the right people that are
actually looking for that issue
with her you know
um my business grows a lot better if I
get people that want to build a coaching
business in the room with me versus just
people that say ah I'm interested in
making a little bit of money on this
internet thing I'm interested in making
a little bit of money on this online
marketing thing because I know it's a
way to make money and I want to make
money from my couch and my underwear and
I want to have a Ferrari without doing
any work right if I get a bunch of those
people into a room they're probably not
going to buy anything from me because
they're lazy and they're not looking for
what I'm actually offering but if I make
sure that my offer copy at top of funnel
is about their problem
and the solution they're looking for I
can attract a whole bunch of those
people
and and then once we dial it in more you
start charging for that
you start charging for your top of
funnel that's what we're now doing with
Rick Pino
that's the level that we've reached now
that I think all of us can get to I'm
not even at that level yet in my own
business but Rick Rick is right now so
he's a great example of this
and he's running free offers but he's
running the free offer to his paid offer
okay so it's it's twenty to fifty
dollars
we used to do these three day events
where we would do a three-day training
so now he's actually charging them a
ticket fee
to listen to him for five days and it's
literally they're paying him to sell
them on his twelve thousand dollar
program
it's costing
pot uh actually now the algorithm is
kicked in with the ads better
two hundred and fifty dollars to get
somebody to give him twenty dollars to
join this
okay so it's called so he's losing two
hundred and thirty dollars on every
single transaction
but
one in five of those transactions is
giving him twelve thousand dollars
so if it's costing him
230 times 5
that's one thousand one hundred and
fifty dollars to make twelve thousand
dollars you get
a hundred people in the room he just
made a hundred grand
on a ten thousand dollar ad spend
and then that scales will spend thirty
thousand and make three hundred thousand
and so that scales that way by doing
that
with
um a model like this but in the
beginning
you don't know are these people actually
gonna sign up so that's why we use free
offers a one-day event or a three day
three days really cool as well if you
just want to go in the deep end because
it's kind of in between
five day is if you're selling something
over two thousand dollars you need five
days
okay
Angie said I recently saw Rick is
building an offer out for a six-figure
business
so uh yes exactly he's actually pivoting
to a new niche
so he launched this right here and I I
actually wrote the copy for it
launch and scale your six figure Kingdom
Business
and so this is a free one day thing he's
actually doing it uh
this afternoon
in two hours
and then he's selling
a paid event that's going to be a
hundred dollars for them to join that's
why he's selling at this free webinar
he's selling that so he's got almost 2
000 people registered for this
and then he's gonna sell them on joining
a hundred dollar five-day event
and then I think he's going to sell like
a 25 000 package at the end of it
did you have a question Monica
oh no I'm shaking my head yes okay it
unmuted you for a second there you go
okay
so so with that though that's why you
want to test with
to hone in your messaging uh free offers
so free offers are gonna be how you can
test out and do that feedback loop so
for every person who joins you for a one
day event on the skin care regimen you
ask the question what is your number one
biggest frustration when it comes to
your skin care you want them to tell you
that then you can literally load that
information into Jasper and it will
summarize it for you
and it will help you craft your copy
around the exact words that they're
using
and so you go top of funnel
now you have people on your email list
you went from not having anyone on your
email list and now you've got a group of
people on an email list
that are qualified around your niche
you got data on what they want
you
got to make them an offer of some kind
if you want if you're just starting out
out
again make them an offer to another
event like a five-day event that's
that's 50 that's 97 bucks or 57 bucks
see how that goes
if it's a one day deal make them a lower
cost offer on a one-day deal
just to test out if people are actually
going to buy from this audience okay and
so then you optimize that and then I
would do again so a free five-day deal
to sell people on a thousand dollar or
two thousand dollar package
and so that becomes your funnel
um
Michelle
let me know what your questions are on
this
thank you that answered everything about
what a funnel is because I'm hearing
people say funnels funnels and I'm like
what is this I was making it more
complicated but you broke it down and
it's like it's so logical and I'm a real
logic person so thank you and let's
break this down even easier I'm going to
show you something really cool
so uh Stephen Robbins who builds all the
funnels for our clients
he actually has created a PDF
on episode number
169 of my podcast
him and I and I put it in the chat here
um let me go put it in the Facebook
group and I'm actually going to pull it
up on screen so him and I did a
discussion where we actually break down
the best funnels for coaches and course
creators
and these are the funnels that literally
this is free on my podcast I need to
make that a whole webinar in and of
itself
so I
I'm telling you if you're like okay I
don't know how to do something Jeremiah
you're in the client growth accelerator
I don't know how to do this maybe you're
on the waiting list to join the client
growth accelerator
um you know after after the first time
here after we open the doors again to it
um you can literally say okay I'm stuck
figuring this out Jeremiah what's a
funnel and I I have podcast episodes
that I've created that walk you through
almost everything in your business
even if you're just starting out trying
to figure it out okay and so keep that
keep that in mind as well let me go I'm
trying to find the Facebook group here
that it's streaming in the client growth
accelerator group so yeah if you guys
want to actually ask your questions live
um go and
and join up in the room I see that
there's about seven people watching in
the Facebook group I'm not gonna
actually check out the questions that
are in the Facebook group that way I'm
finding I need to uh pay attention to
who's in the zoom room and then I'll
answer questions later in the chat
afterwards
um okay so I'm going to share this
screen on this now
and I'm going to pull this up for you
and this is going to make things very
easy for you very simple
this will walk you through I'm telling
you I I have resources that walk you
through everything
um it might and they might not even be
paid resources they might literally be
my podcast
my thing is is that if if I don't have
it as a paid resource I usually end up
making it a podcast so at least now I do
have a resource because I can roll out
podcasts like in a week you know so I
don't have to build a whole course
around it it's like an overview okay so
episode 169 funnels that make seven
figures and this is also for those that
want to make six figures and so we break
this down in the episode
um and you can contact Stephen as well
to build out your funnels
um I think he's I think he's like
40 bucks an hour or something
on that so but he's really good he
builds out all of Rick's all of Joshua's
all of mine
and so there's this PDF right here that
you can access
um
with this
and this is funnel Maps so we actually
created a map for you
for your funnels so we got your opt-in
page right here
a welcome series of emails and Steven
breaks all of this down in the video
training in the video okay
and you can check this PDF out um I'll
put it in the chat here
I'm gonna put this in the chat right
there
I need to actually have the Facebook
group open in a window so I can
at least paste stuff into that group
okay so there's the PDF
to that the funnels PDF
um
funnels PDF I'm gonna post that in the
group
those that are in there and I'm going to
post
funnels podcast episode with
I'm gonna tag Steven he's in the group
he's you can message him I've known
Stephen for
13 yeah see for 13 years 14 years almost
and um yeah what we found is that when
we give this to people it all makes
sense to them
um I probably should actually Implement
what I'm showing right now
into my five day training
[Laughter]
like I say yes yeah I think it would
actually help people see the visual and
give this away in that as well okay so
then what you have is you have the
welcome series of emails we send an
email four times to people when they opt
in
because they literally ignore the first
email and we have found that we have 50
of the people actually join a free event
or or download a free something by doing
that and then MailChimp we set it up to
where if they didn't click the link in
the email from the email the day before
they're gonna get sent another one and
we just changed the subject line of each
of those emails to say you're in and
then here's how you get your login
details here's the download that you
registered for and then the last one's
like last chance to get in and they're
kind of like alert alert and that's what
helps people get in that's what helps
people actually jump into it
you will this is just percentages on
your free offer in your funnel
you're only ever going to have
um
like 77 of your people actually join
your free training
like or like 66 like 33 of everyone who
registers for a free training with you
is not even gonna use it go through it
or anything
so that's normal
and the numbers that I got 10 registered
is a really high number okay
um most of you are actually going to
have about two to three percent that
come into your free stuff are going to
pay you
when you're starting out and you will
get up to the 10 level
um if it's a if it's a paid challenge
twenty percent is not is a good number
normal
um because
if they paid they're definitely showing
signs that they're more interested for
sure
okay I see Andrew just sent a message to
Stephen rut yes Steven's amazing be sure
to connect with Stephen
and so that's why we send out these
emails when we do our free top of funnel
offer and this could be a uh these are
different funnels by the way this PDF is
awesome three day challenge
free ebook
free mini class these are all top of
funnel
core offer okay membership High ticket
next steps
okay
so these so a three-day challenge Boot
Camp or even a five day
uh or a one day are actually all
essentially the exact same funnel
whether it be one day three days five
days seven days ten days 21 days
I actually did a 21 day uh two years ago
when covid started
every single person who went through all
21 days became a paid one-on-one
coaching client of mine
I was able to add like 10K to our our
business that month and I had like never
seen those kind of numbers and that was
just like randomly doing like 21 days of
training for people
in a Facebook group
so the funnel is going to be the same
for whether it be a one day a three day
a five day or whatever
an upsell is optional but it is
recommended to where you have like a VIP
that they jump into to ask you questions
because those people are going to be
more qualified to buy whatever it is
that you're offering at the end of it
now here's I'm doing I'm doing a test on
my little uh free deal that I'm offering
this this weekend that I'm gonna that
I'm gonna be putting out there this um
starting your own six-figure coaching
business one finding your Niche I'm
gonna have a seven dollar VIP on my free
webinar
seven bucks you get an extra hour with
me to ask questions because it's only a
one day they're not getting all five
days
but but then the goal is I'm going to be
sending them to another free thing so
I'm not really wanting them to invest a
whole lot in this level I want them Do
It Best in the 47 on the other one
and then they're going to be made to
offer to join the client growth
accelerator for two grand at the end of
it and that'll be sometime like in a
month from now okay
um
in our funnel we open and close the
doors of our paid offer
um just because
it incentivizes people to actually take
action instead of wait until next time
and then another way to do that is you
can create special bonuses like for
instance those that joined and you got
this funnels and offer copy live
um I'm gonna make an event like this
exclusive
four people who actually joined and then
everybody else if you've gone through
one with me is gonna actually have to
probably pay an additional ticket fee to
join
um because it's going to be exclusive
like for new members type of a thing
as as the goal that's what I'm going to
be building my offer launch pad it'll be
a probably a 300 event that I'm going to
end up doing
for two days but then people get it
exclusive those two days when they join
the program I'm going to run it
quarterly just once a quarter
as an upsell as part of my main offer
okay so you have your thank you page
you have upsell an upsell follow-up
where you actually have in your
follow-up you're trying to Loop them
right back up into your upsell
um you mentioned your upsell each day of
your free event at the beginning of it
you can like even start if it's a one
day say Hey listen there's still a
chance those that want to jump in you
get about 30 minutes into a two-hour
presentation say Hey listen it's only
seven bucks love to work with you at the
end they're already excited a whole
bunch of people will jump in right there
and so you keep looping people back to
the VIP because it qualifies their
interest when people give you money when
they actually take even seven bucks 47
bucks and invest it with you they're
more committed now to the words that
you're saying
because they want to get their money's
worth
how many of you like what like you want
to watch something on Netflix if you pay
for Netflix because you're you're paying
that monthly fee so I'm going to watch
at least one movie this month on it for
two movies or something like that or you
order something off of Amazon because
you're paying for Prime right so you're
you know by paying for something even if
it's a little amount well we end up
using what we paid for more than if we
didn't pay for it we don't people don't
respect it
now if they got it as a bonus for
something they paid for they do respect
it as well but the people that are
actually paying you for something really
respect what they paid for they want to
get their money's worth they want to
know that they're getting their money's
worth okay and so wow that was
absolutely incredible listen make sure
that you check out the PDF as well check
out the podcast I did with Steven
episode number 169. consider hiring him
to build out your funnels and if you
want more help from me right now you
might have to join the waiting list for
the client growth accelerator we have so
many people in there there's a lot of
people asking to be on the waiting list
but go to jeremicarkowski.com put your
name in for the waiting list when we
open the doors back to this this is my
Premier group coaching program where I'm
helping coaches trainers course creators
mentors grow their businesses and scale
to seven and eight figures if you want
to skip that all together you can
schedule a discovery call with me and we
can do one-on-one coaching together now
one-on-one coaching is four thousand
seven hundred fifty dollars a month you
get 2 two sessions with me and we work
together doing that we also have the
funnel and offer copy audit which is
three thousand dollars over at my
website and that's for people that if
you want somebody to look over your
funnel if you want me to go over it if
you want me to write some of your copy
for you you want Stephen to look at your
funnel and this is like hiring us to
take a bird's eye view of your business
and help you do that that might be a
really good investment for those of you
so you can find all those resources as
well as my courses as well as my
coaching and the podcast episodes from
this podcast for almost that episode on
number 180 there's so many episodes in
this podcast that can help you grow your
business don't miss out check them out
share them with somebody and we'll see
you next week here on the grow Your Life
podcast have a good one everybody